# Michael Paul Noseworthy, B.Eng.

138 Great Eastern Avenue St. John's, NL A1B 0J8 mike.noseworthy@gmail.com +1 (709) 693-3149 https://ca.linkedin.com/in/michaelnoseworthy https://github.com/noseworthy

#### Summary

Talented software developer and technical leader with a unique combination of strong leadership skills along with a passion for technical innovation and problem solving. Experienced in leading a customer focused development team and solving customer pain points by engaging cross departmental teams.

#### **Technical Skills**

#### **Programming**

- Python (Expert): 3 years of professional experience using Scrapy, Flask, and Tornado
- C/C++ (Proficient): 2 years of professional and academic experience
- Java (Proficient): 4 years of academic experience
- JavaScript (Familiar): 3 years of professional experience
- HTML (Familiar): 3 years of professional experience
- Perl (Familiar): 1 year of professional experience
- Objective-C (Familiar): 1 year of academic experience
- Ruby (Newbie): 3 months of experience with personal projects using Rails
- Go (Newbie): Just started learning I have a personal interest in the language

#### Infrastructure and Tools

- Amazon Web Services (Proficient): 3 years of professional experience with EC2, SQS, DynamoDB, Route53, etc.
- MongoDB and PostgreSQL (Proficient): 3 years of professional experience
- Git (Expert): 5 years of professional and academic experience with git and github.com
- OSX and Linux (Proficient): 5 years of professional and academic experience using and building applications on an OSX and Ubuntu Server platforms

## **Professional Skills**

- **Team Leadership**: 1.5 years of professional experience leading a customer focused software development team
- Scrum Agile Development Methodology: 3 years of professional experience delivering software products using Scrum
- Customer Focus: 2 years of professional experience working on and eventually leading a customer service focused software development team

#### Professional Training and Conferences

- Attended PyCon 2014 and 2015 in Montreal, QC
- Represented 360pi at the 2014 Canadian University Software Engineering Conference (CUSEC) in Montreal, QC
- Completed MITACS' "Foundations of Project Management I" training seminar in January, 2013

### Employment History

#### Technical Services Manager – 360pi Corporation (Ottawa, ON)

[January 2015 – August 2015]

- Provided both technical and non-technical leadership for a team of 6 software developers
- Worked with project managers and product managers to specify customer requirements and design solutions
- Improved the focus and performance of the Technical Services Team. This was measured by increased resolution time of high priority customer issues and customer implementation tickets
- Responsible for managing the human resources of the team. Interviewed over 40 candidates for the Technical Services Developer role and hired top candidates
- Presented reports to Execs and Management on the Technical Services Team performance at Quarterly Business Review meetings
- Performed evaluations of team members including performing monthly one-on-one check-in, quarterly goal review, and yearly goal setting meetings
- Simultaneously performed all the responsibilities of the Technical Services Team Lead in addition to the responsibilities as manager

#### Technical Services Team Lead – 360pi Corporation (Ottawa, ON)

[April 2014 – January 2015]

- Lead a team of 6 software developers with a focus on customer service and integration
- Acted as a liaison between non-technical customer service and sales personnel and development team
- Ensured customer high priority customer issues were addressed in a timely manner, being reviewed and triaged within an hour of receipt and resolved within 24 hours on average by the team
- Provided technical insight to customer service and sales personnel when dealing with customer issues and new implementations
- Designed solutions to customer issues and worked with development to design new product features

#### Software Developer – 360pi Corporation (Ottawa, ON)

[November 2012 - April 2014]

- Worked as part of a small team developing web scraping and price intelligence software
- Wrote and maintained web scrapers which extracted product and price information from online retailers
- Developed tools and infrastructure to aid in web scraping activities
- Developed price intelligence software in Python using web frameworks such as Flask and Tornado and deployed code to cloud services such as Amazon AWS, Rackspace, and Digital Ocean
- Utilized both SQL and NoSQL database technology such as PostgreSQL and MongoDB

## Wireless Data Application Developer (Co-op) – Research In Motion (Kanata, ON)

[January 2011 – April 2011 and September 2011 – December 2011]

- Developed embedded software for BlackBerry targeting wireless 3GPP and 3GPP2 protocols (CDMA, GSM, UMTS, HSPA)
- Worked with a team of talented developers in design, implementation, testing, and integration of features
- Performed verification and validation testing of features

# Junior Design Engineer (Co-op) – Avalon Microelectronics (Mount Pearl, NL) [April 2010 – August 2010]

- Performed verification of standard compliance on a 40G SONET IP core and 1.25G OTN core, targeting FPGA technology
- Verified over 230 requirements in under 3 months, completing approximately 50% in three weeks
- · Presented verification reports to team leaders and members at weekly team meetings
- Applied knowledge of the SONET standard, and project requirements in the development of detailed test cases for the 40G SONET project

# Software Developer (Co-op) – Research In Motion (Kanata, ON)

[January 2009 - April 2009 and September 2009 - December 2009]

- Performed daily sanity tests on software for the Blackberry Operating System's radio protocol stacks and RIM Java Virtual Machine native interfaces
- Developed scripting tools that performed automated build and testing functions to improve the efficiency of the team

## Education

#### Memorial University of Newfoundland, St. John's, NL

[September 2006 – May 2012]

- Completed 6-year Bachelor of Engineering program with major in Computer Engineering
- Achieved 83.4% average with a GPA of 3.79 (out of 4.0)
- Received the Dean's List Award which acknowledges the top performing 10% of the class Received 2<sup>nd</sup> place at IEEE Presentation night for senior design project entitled, "Scape: An Audio Augmented Reality Framework and Application" on March 26, 2012
- Received the PEGNL Cossitt Award for outstanding performance on a senior work term placement as nominated by the employer on March 27, 2012 valued at \$500
- Received 8 other scholarships for academic excellence

## Extra Curricular Activities

- Founder of NDev, a software development focused Meetup group for software developers in St. John's. Newfoundland and Labrador
- Active in Ottawa software development community, specifically Ottawa Python Author's Group (OPAG)
- Currently training for the 2016 Ironman Frankfurt triathlon
- Current Member of IEEE Canada

References available upon request.